talkandroid.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy | TalkAndroid.com

_Talk Android_ and its Operators, Canuck Digital Media Inc., understand and fully respect the privacy of our readers and visitors.  The privacy of our readers is important to us, and to keep you informed of our privacy practices, we have provided this document disclosing Canuck Digital Media Inc.’s intent, purpose, and use of any information that is potentially private, as well as providing details of how this information is gathered.

At _Talk Android_ , we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

This document was last updated on May 28, 2018.

**Disclosure of Information**

Users of _Talk Android_ are never asked to disclose information involuntarily, except whatever information is always disclosed by browsers, servers, and internet traffic as part of the normal operation of a website.  Some of that information automatically disclosed is explained under heading “Log Files” and “Cookies and Web Beacons.” _Talk Android_ does not collect private information from its users without their knowledge.

**What personal information do we collect and why?**

Some parts of the site, such as our forums and our contests may require that we collect some information such as your email or your name. That information is always disclosed voluntarily, we do not require it for you to read the content on our site.

Contest Winners may be asked to send us their email addresses and/or shipping information. This information is strictly kept private, and is only used to be able to ship out contest prizes.

Users who subscribe to our newsletter are required to provide an email and possibly a name. We use this information in order to send out the newsletter. By signing up to our newsletter, you consent to our use of your information for this purpose.

**Keeping Information Safe  
**Canuck Digital Media Inc. takes all reasonable precautions to keep our information safe, including limiting who has access to that information. The _Talk Android_ editorial team and staff do NOT have access to private information stored in our logs or servers. The editorial team also make their best efforts to preserve the privacy of any persons they communicate with in the course of their work on the site.

**Log Files**  
As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.  
**  
Cookies, Web Beacons, Google Analytics and Third Party Ads**  
We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.  This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We make use of 3rd party Google Analytics to get an idea of how our site is used and to help us improve our content.  Certain information such as your browser, and your IP address may be sent to Analytics but this information is always anonymized so that we don’t know which specific visitors are associated with what browser and we do not have access to any IP information in Analytics.  Analytics may use several cookies in order to determine if you have visited the site before, but Analytics never associates any identifiable information with your visit.  So we may know many people read a particular article, but we won’t know specifically who read it.

To opt out of being counted in Google Analytics, you can [install a browser add on made by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We also use third party advertisements on _Talk Android_ to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can control Ad Personalisation by Google Ads and Google products by visiting the [Google Ad Settings page](https://adssettings.google.com/).

You can also learn more about third party advertiser personalisation of ads and [opt out of personalisation by seeing this opt out page.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

**DoubleClick DART cookies**  
We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information.” It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

**Google’s Use of Information**

Because we use Google services such as Google Ads and Google Analytics, you can read more about Google’s use of information in [their disclosure here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

**Privacy Contact Info:**

If you ever need to contact us about a Privacy concern, please write to us below.  We take privacy seriously and would like to hear from you.

**Canuck Digital Media Inc.**  
PO Box 27531  
Oakridge  
Vancouver, BC  
V5Z 4M4
